TO WHOM IT MAY CONCERN,

I would like to apply for a role in the "At Home Advisor College Program".

I have been studying Full Stack Software Development with UCD Professional Academy since September 2021. All of my coursework is being done with a self-learning approach. This means I have to be extremely organized and use my study time as efficiently as possible. I am required to work to strict deadlines with my projects. This is being done part-time as I am also working full time as a Carpenter.

I possess several years of work experience in different roles. This has given me the opportunity to gain valuable skills such as communication and customer service which was essential while working as a bartender and waiter. I also made use of these skills while working as a carpenter as I would be meeting clients on a daily basis. I thrive in fast paced environments and I work well in teams. I am an excellent timekeeper and as I work for a family business, I am always the first to work to open up the building site.

I have a passion for technology and tech products, and I am very eager to learn new skills. I currently have an iPhone 11 Pro and a 2021 14-inch MacBook Pro M1.

Thank you for considering me for this role,

Seán Tangney.



My Personal Website

SEÁN TANGNEY

Gortgloss, Scartaglen, Killarney, Co. Kerry, Ireland V93DD82 ◆ 087 9678662 ◆ sean tangney@hotmail.com

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Carpenter with 6+ years of experience in the construction industry. Full Stack Software Development Student with UCD Professional Academy.

WORK HISTORY

Carpenter, 10/2019 to Current

Pat & Joe Tangney Building Contractors LTD – Scartaglen, Kerry

- Worked on a variety of projects from start to finish including garages, residential homes, and extensions.
- Proactively helped manage projects and organized materials.
- Have been involved in marking out, preparing and pouring foundations for houses. Pouring concrete subfloors and finished floors. Roofing. Drywalling. Shuttering. Footpaths. Percolations. Landscaping.
- I have regularly and competently carried out work using machinery such as a telehandler, digger, and dumper.
- Worked as part of a team to ensure that work is carried out on time and to a high standard.
- I have experience dealing with clients and have always upheld a positive, professional relationship with them.

Apprentice Carpenter, 10/2015 to 10/2019

Pat & Joe Tangney Building Contractors LTD – Scartaglen, Kerry

- Maintained a clean working environment on job sites.
- Learned how to use hand and power tools properly and safely.
- Worked with qualified carpenters and helped them complete various tasks.
- Assisted with project planning.
- Attended college for one 20-week period and two 10 week periods during my apprenticeship.

Bartender and Waiter, 04/2015 to 04/2018

Heights Hotel – Killarney, Kerry

- I worked here in the evenings after work and on weekends.
- Served food and drinks for crowds of up to 400 people at weddings and other events.
- Maintained full knowledge of bar and menu items and made recommendations.
- Set up rooms and tables for large crowds attending various events.
- Performed closing duties including cleaning, sanitizing and replenishing.
- Often worked long hours here after a full day on a building site.

Line Operator, 01/2015 to 09/2015

Munster Joinery – Ballydesmond, Cork

- Worked as part of a team to ensure we adeptly handled the high pace of a factory environment.
- Responsibilities included glazing the windows and cutting and installing the beads to hold them in place.

SKILLS

- Carpentry
- General construction
- Problem-solving
- Project management
- Multi-tasking
- Customer Service

- Extremely organized
- Self-motivated
- Work well in a team
- Communication skills
- Time management

EDUCATION —
Carpentry & Joinery, 2019
Solas - Ireland
• An apprenticeship comprised of on-site and off-site experience for a duration of 4 years.
Professional Diploma in Full-Stack Software Development, 10/2021 to Present
UCD Professional Academy – Ireland
• I am currently studying to become a Software Developer. Upon completion of this course in October 2022, I will have dual certification from UCD Professional Academy and Code Institute.
• During this one-year course I will build a portfolio by completing 5 milestone projects. These projects will all be created by me using the new skills I have acquired.
 HTML fundamentals
 CSS fundamentals
 User-centric front-end development
 JavaScript fundamentals
 Interactive front-end development
 Python fundamentals
o Practical Python
o Data-centric development
 Full-stack frameworks with Django
ACCOMPLISHMENTS —
• Successfully completed the leaving cert course in 2014.
• Qualified as a Carpenter.
Have a full clean Irish driving license.
• Won several trophies with the local GAA team.
FURTHER SKILLS —
• Familiar with both iOS and Windows operating systems.

- I have created a website using HTML and CSS and JavaScript and I have deployed the final version of the website to a cloud-based hosting platform.
- I have completed projects using Bootstrap and Python.